AVRIL WONG

http://wongavril.com/

CONTACT

Mobile

(408) 784-8916

Email

wongavril@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/avrilwong/



SKILLS

Visual Design
UI/UX Design
User Research & Testing
Brand Strategy & Identity
Information Architecture
Personas & User Stories
Wireframing & Prototyping
Data analysis & Visualization



TOOLS

Adobe Creative Suite

Sketch

Figma

InVision

HTML, CSS

Javascript

Keynote

Numbers



LANGUAGES

English
Cantonese
Mandarin

Korean

ABOUT ME

I am an app specialist/UX enthusiast. I have a strong background in marketing and deep knowledge in problem-solving, sprinkles of aesthetics is always a plus.

Four years of experience working with World Wide Developer Relations at Apple, I have been serving as different roles in the cross-functional team. From operation, audit, critical decision making to new-hire metorship.



EXPERIENCE

APPLE INC.

July 2015 - Current

World Wide Developer Relations

- Collaborate closely with designers, developers and project managers to provide user-centric solutions and critical marketing decisions
- Review app content and reliability based on a set of technical, content, and design criteria to ensure quality is up to standard
- Support performance audit and new-hire mentorship, maintain team performance and SLA at 95%

Localization QA Specialist

- Supported Apple Music's global launch project in Asia from producing pre-launch materials to performing post-launch testing
- Created and localized marketing content in the various channel
- Performed quality assurance on user experience throughout the entire project

FOREVER 21July 2014 - Jan 2015

Visual Merchandiser

- Spearheaded marketing campaigns to raise brand awareness
- Increased daily sales for 15% by designing strategic floor setup and display system

MELCO CROWN ENTERTAINMENT

June 2012 - July 2014

Contract Management Coordinator

- Drafted, reviewed, managed a wide variety of inbound and outbound contracts, including vendor agreements, professional services agreements, work orders and related purchase requisitions, and miscellaneous agreements
- Negotiated with service providers and saved over \$100K annually

EDUCATION

BLOC 2018 - 2019

Product Design and Front-End Development Program

UNIVERSITY OF MACAU

2008 - 2012

Bachelor's degree, Business Administration - Marketing